Guide to the Alan Sondheim Papers MSS.267
Fales Library and Special Collections
Alan Sondheim Papers
1965-2002
Fales Library and Special Collections
Sondheim, Alan
MSS.267
55.5 Linear Feet in 52 records cartons, 6 flat boxes, 1 small cassette box, and 1 large reel
95 sound tape reels 94 1/4" audio reels and 1 1/2" audio reel
215 audiocassettes 214 compact cassettes and 1 microcassette
45 film reels 15 8mm films, 4 super8 films, 21 16mm films, 4 35mm films, 1 offsite film
87 videoreels (1/2 inch)
100 videocassettes (u-matic)
7 videocassettes (betamax)
1 videocassettes (betacam)
124 videocassettes (vhs)
3 videocassettes (minidv)
2 sound discs (vinyl)
21 electronic discs (cd-rom)
16 dvd-r disks
2 3.5" floppy disks
1 media elements 1 hard drive
9 items 9 artifacts
Box 1
Box 2
Box 3
Box 4
Box 5
Box 6
Box 7
Box 8
Box 9
Box 10
Box 11
Box 12
Box 13
Box 14
Box 15
Box 16
Box 17
Box 18
Box 19
Box 20
Box 21
Box 22
Box 23
Box 24
Box 25
Box 26
Box 27
Box 28
Box 29
Box 30
Box 31
Box 32
Box 33
Box 34
Box 35
Box 36
Box 37
Box 38
Box 39
Box 40
Box 41
Box 42
Box 43
Box 44
Box 45
Box 46
Box 47
Box 48
Box 49
Box 50
Box 51
Box 52
Box 53
Box 54
Box 55
Box 56
Box 57
Box 58
Box Quarantine 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Alan Sondheim in April, 2010; the accession number associated with this collection is 2009-267.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact [Fales, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies. To request that material be transferred, or if you are unsure if material has been transferred, please contact [Fales, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596] with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Cyberspace |x Political aspects.; Art and the internet -- Exhibitions; Computer art.; Digital art |z United States.; New media art.; Video art -- United States.; Experimental films -- United States; Slides (Photography); Gender identity -- United States; Feminist theory.
- Series I. Written Work
- Series II. Visual Art
- Series III. Musical Recordings
- Series IV. Film and Video Recordings
  - Found Footage, 1950-1984 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_001)
    Scope and Contents
    Label on original can says "0. Washington D.C. 1950; 1. 1950 found footage; 2. Corporate film '84?"
  - .1., July, 1970 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_003)
  - Car, July, 1970 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_002)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: Super 8 mm
  - Oscelloscope Films, 1970-1975 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_005)
    Original can label says "1. 2 x 3 Oscelloscope Waveform; 2. Nova Scotia Gestmal [?] Work; 3. Orseus; 4. Beth Doubled; 5. wh SEM; 6. Oscelloscope over TV, Overlaw Talking Heads; 7. Oscelloscope; 8. Chris and Don; 1972? - 1973 - 1974?"
  - 4-3-2-0 Spacing: Brown University, 1973; cuid21360 (Box 25)
    Format: EIAJ 1/2" Open Reel Video, Duration: 30 min.
  - Additional footage from The Blue Tape, 1974; cuid21359 (Box 35, Reel cuid21359)
    Additional footage from the Kathy Acker/Alan Sondheim video work "The Blue Tape." The tape is labeled "acker/sondheim satire/part 1."
  - Travel Footage - Southwest and Northeast U.S., 1975-1981 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_008)
    Original reel label says: "0. Introduction 1981; 1. Caldera, Los Alamos; 2. Pueblo ruin / Atomic Museum; 3. UCLA / Santa Monica; 4. NYC / Staten Island Market View; 5. Far Hills, N.J. '75; 6. S.E.M., Nova Scotia 77? 7. Instrumenalists, '81?"
  - Theses After Marx Red Art Brigade, 1976; cuid21361 (Box 16)
  - Laura, 1979 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_006, 267_009)
  - Hollywood -- Dup 1, Reel 2 of 2, 1981 (Reel mss267_container6)
  - Hollywood, 1981 (Box 10, 16mm film reels 267_011, 267_012)
  - 35mm Master Negatives, 1981 (Box 4, 35mm film reels 267_010)
  - Talking Cure, 1982 (Box 10, 16mm film reels 267_013)
  - This Is the Film in Which You Are Forgiven and This Is the Film in Which I Am Lost, 1982-1984 (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_015)
    Original film can label says "Pia -- This is the film in which you are forgiven; This is the film in which I am lost; Silent 16-18 fps; 1982-1983; Alan Sondheim"
  - Tasmanian Master, 1983 (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_014)
  - One Day in the Life of Tryon, 1985 (Box 36, 16mm film reels 267_016)
  - Dallas Silent Footage, 1987 (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_017)
  - She Came in and Out of Me - Film the End, 1987 (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_018)
  - Angelina, 1989 (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_019)
  - Color Video Master, Undated (Box 10, 16mm film reels 267_020)
  - Compilation Film (Box 36, 16mm film reels 267_007)
    Original film can label says "1973 Compilation Film; Before Tasmania 1981; Hartford Footage / Laura"
  - Fold Catastrophe, Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_027)
  - Georgian Bay, Undated (Box 36, 16mm film reels 267_028)
  - Joanne - yr 300 footage, Halifax footage, Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_029, 267_030)
  - NYC FG Waterfall ACA Briarcliff Shreveport, Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_024)
  - Old Moving Car Footage, Punk Footage, Undated (Box 36, 16mm film reels 267_004)
  - S.E.M. Imagery, Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_034)
  - Short Road Bit, Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_036)
  - Some Fall Shots, Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_035)
  - Work of Inferno [?], Undated (Box 4, 8mm film reel 267_023)
  - World War II Canadian Training Film, Undated (Box 36, 16mm film reels 267_022)
  - Way Out West, Undated (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_026)
  - Untitled Film, 1985 (Box 36, 16mm film reels 267_031)
  - Unlabeled, Undated (Box 11, 16mm film reels 267_021, Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_025, 267_037, 267_038, 267_039, 35mm film reels 267_032, 267_033)
- Series V. Events
  - Brown University MCM 170 Class, c. 2007 (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_040)
  - Brown University Intro Film, c. 2007 (Box 4, 16mm film reels 267_041)